Jeff Brozena

jeff@brozena.net | +1 (570)335-8269

SUMMARY

An operator and teacher with 5+ years in strategic alignment/systems integration, software training, and change management at one of the country's largest privately-held Medicaid pediatric dental groups. With over 50,000 appointments seen per year and little chance for downtime, I stewarded the group from paper-based record-keeping to full digitization, and was entrusted to set strategic direction, improve core business processes and lead complex change shortly before a cross-generational ownership transfer was expected. I leveraged software integration to catalyze systemic organizational change at scale.

EDUCATION

The Pennsylvania State University

Dec 2019

BS - Information Sciences & Technology

EXPERIENCE

Wellbeing and Health Innovation Lab, College of IST — University Park, PA

Sep 2019 — present

Research Support

 Developing a conceptual and technical framework in Python to detect mental health states using multi-modal data streams reflecting online activities.

The Smilist Management — Great Neck, NY

Feb 2018 — Aug 2018

Manager of Optimization

- Discovered, documented, and re-engineered core business processes at dental service organization containing 20+ locations in the New York metro area.
- Conducted root cause analyses via individual/group interviews after quickly establishing rapport with stakeholders at all levels of management.
- Reduced city and state compliance risk at all sites.
- Drafted requirements for in-house analytics platform.

Smiles 4 Keeps Pediatric Dentistry — Scranton, PA

Aug 2012 - Nov 2017

Practice Operations

- Transformed one of the country's largest privately-held multi-site dental groups from paper-based, siloed locations to a streamlined, integrated, centralized, digitized operation.
- Fostered trust with multiple owners across several years, served as strategic counsel in technical and non-technical capacities.
- Completed a sequence of practice management software data conversions at all sites, coordinating between internal management and external vendors.
- Identified and voiced the cultural need for standardization across business processes and technical systems, earning the trust of ownership, management, and hundreds of employees.
- Continued to lead a sequence of employee-facing projects which leveraged the centralized environment for
 continuous improvement, stewarding software development to meet enterprise-level business needs, personally
 training all layers of management and staff.
- Integrated best-of-breed dental analytics platform into daily workflows, creating conditions for legacy understandings to evolve into data-driven decision-making.
- Presented to thousands of pediatric dentists at the American Academy of Pediatric Dentistry on the subjects of digitization and compliant record-keeping.

Bedrock Technology — Scranton, PA

Jan 2012 — Aug 2012

Technician

Penn State University — University Park, PA Software Trainer

Aug 2007 — Dec 2009

• Promoted to supervisory position in June, 2009.

VOLUNTEERING

Active Minds at Penn State - Founding President

Sep 2010 — May 2011

- Founded Penn State University Park's chapter of the nationwide mental health awareness group Active Minds
- Designed and prototyped a mobile web application to promote mental health resource utilization on campus.
- Served as a direct point of contact to campus newspapers and other news outlets including the Associated Press - giving interviews and speaking at length about our mission.

AWARDS

Rock Ethics Stand Up Award, Penn State University

Apr 2011

Emerging Scholars Fellowship, Active Minds, Inc.

Jan 2011

SKILLS

Leadership: Public speaking, Systems thinking, Whole systems management, Written & verbal clarity, Motivational interviewing, Situational leadership

Digital transformation: Software training, Transformational change, Change management, Strategic planning, Business analysis

Healthcare information technology (HIT): HIPAA compliance, Electronic data interchange (EDI), Electronic medical record (EMR),
Analytics, SQL, Product management, Systems integration, Software integration, Electronic remittance advice (ERA), Clinical decision support

Program management: Process improvement, Project management, Process optimization, Process management, Lean Six Sigma, Kaizen